Here you are.
WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
The sea snake is going
to die, isn't he?
Luke.
It can't be Lord of the Tides.
Grandsire was the greatest
sailor who ever lived.
I get green sick before the
ship even leaves the harbour.
I'll just ruin everything.
I don't want Driftmark.
It should have passed
on to surveyman.
We don't choose our destiny,
Luke. It chooses us.
Grandsire, let you choose
whether you be as a...
You told us so.
And do you want to
know the truth of it?
I was frightened.
I was four and ten.
Same as you are now.
I wasn't ready to be queen
of the Seven Kingdoms.
But it was my duty, and in time I came to
understand I had to earn my inheritance.
I'm not like you.
In what way, sweet boy?
Not so...
perfect.
I am anything but.
My father looked after me and
helped prepare me for my duties.
Your mother will do
the same for you.
Good morrow, Princess.
Good morrow, Sir Laurent.
Princess Renise has just
arrived on Dragonback.
We urgently request an audience
with you and Prince Daemon.
The Princess Rhaenys Targaryen.
Thank you, Sir Laurence.
Princess Rhaenys, might we hope
for news of Lord Corlys's recovery?
Viserys is dead.
I grieve this loss
with you, Rhaenyra.
My cousin. Your father.
Possessed a kind heart.
There is more.
Aegon has been crowned
as his successor.
They crowned him.
How did Viserys die?
I could not say.
How long ago?
A day past, perhaps two.
I was made a prisoner in my quarters
while the Queen made her preparations.
Viserys has been slain.
Alicent demanded you
declare for Aegon.
She did.
I refused her.
And yet you are alive.
The High Septon crowned
Aegon in the Dragonpit.
I witnessed it myself just
before I fled on Maelys.
They crowned him
before the masses.
So that the masses would see
him as their rightful king.
That whore of a queen murdered my brother and stole
his throne, and you could have burned more for it.
A war is like to be fought over
this treachery, to be sure.
But that war is
not mine to begin.
I only rushed this warning to you out of
loyalty to my husband and to my house.
The greens are coming
for you, Rhaenyra.
And for your children.
You should leave
Dragonstone at once.
Baby's coming.
Her term is far from complete.
This should not be happening.
It is fucking happening!
Keep your head
about you, Princess.
Come.
You've done this
five times before.
Keep your spirit in the
sixth volume, different.
Get off! Get off! Get off!
I want patrols along the island's perimeter,
looking for any small ships that might set
ashore.
If the Greens attack now, it
will be by stealth, not directly.
We don't have enough men to surround the island,
but we can make ourselves appear stronger
than they are.
Conscript the Dragon Keepers, they're
capable fighters, waste no time.
It will be done, my prince.
What was that?
I'm sorry.
You might go easier
on him, my prince...
so he can learn what
you're trying to teach.
Your lady mother
needs to see you.
Both of you.
Mother?
Oh, fuck.
Princess.
Your grandson, King
Viserys, has passed.
Viserys?
The Greens have repudiated the
succession and claimed the Iron Throne.
Aegon has been crowned king.
What is to be done about it?
Nothing yet.
And where is Daemon?
I don't know. Gone to madness.
Gone to plot his war.
Leave Daemon with me.
Jace.
Whatever claim remains to
me, you are now its heir.
Nought is to be done
but by my command.
The raven flew in this morning, the sea snake's
fever is broken and he has left Edenfall.
Where is he sailing?
That much is unclear, my prince.
We'll send ravens to
our nearest allies.
Lords Darkling, Massey...
and Bar-Emon.
Do you want to speak to
the maester, my prince?
I'll fly to the riverlands myself
and affirm Lord Tully's support.
You will do no such thing.
My mother has decreed no action
be taken while she's a bed.
It's good you're
here, young prince.
You're needed to patrol
the skies on Vyrmax.
Did you hear what I said?
The ravens, Lord Bartimus.
I shall see it done.
Summon to Stefan. Our King's Guard
are needed on the Dragonland.
Come with me. I'll show you
the true meaning of loyalty.
You swore an oath as
Knights of the King's Guard.
As do all who wear the
White Cloak, my Prince.
To whom?
I swore first to King
Jehaerys, my Prince.
And then, to his grace, King
Viserys, when he succeeded him.
Do you acknowledge the
true line of succession?
Yes. Yes, my prince.
Do you recall
how King Viserys named his
his heir before his death?
Princess Rhaenyra.
I'm grateful for your
long service to the Crown.
So I'm presenting
you with a choice.
I swear anew your oath to
Rhaenyra as your queen,
to Prince De Ceres as the
heir to the Iron Throne.
Or if you support the
usurper speaker now,
then you will have a clean
and honourable death.
But if you choose treachery,
if you swear fealty now only
to later turn your cloaks,
know that you will die
Screaming.
Princess, let us help you.
Princess, please.
You shouldn't do
this alone, Princess.
Let us help you.
I mean no harm of us.
I swear toward the Queen,
With all my strength...
and give my blood for hers,
I shall take no wife...
hold no lands,
father no children.
I shall guard her secrets,
obey her commands,
ride at her side, and
defend her name and
and honor.
My Queen.
Queen Rhaenyra Targaryen,
first of her name.
Queen of the Andals and the
Rhoynar and the First Men.
Lady of the Seven Kingdoms
and protector of the realm.
Your Grace.
Wine, my queen.
Thank you, Reyna.
Come.
What is our standing?
We have 30 knights, 100
crossbowmen, and 300 men-at-arms.
Dragonstone is relatively
easy to defend,
but as an instrument
of conquest,
our army leaves a
lot to be desired.
I've sent word to my loyal
men in the City Watch.
I'll have some support there,
but I cannot speak
to the numbers.
We already have declarations
from Kelty, Gale, and Staunton,
Massey, Darkland, and Barremont.
My lady mother was in Arran.
The Vale will not turn
cloak against their own kin.
River Run was always
a close friend
to your father, Your Grace.
With Prince Daemon's
acquiescence...
I've already sent
ravens to Lord Grover.
Lord Grover is fickle
and easily swayed.
He will need to be convinced
of the strength of our position
and that we will support
him should it come to war.
I'm going to treat
with him myself.
What of Storm's
End and Winterfell?
There has never lived a
Stark who forgot an oath,
and with how Stark
the North will follow.
Lord Boros Baratheon will need to be
reminded of his father's promises.
What news from Driftmark?
Lord Caller sails
for Dragonstone.
To declare for his Queen?
The Valarion fleet is
in my husband's yoke.
He decides where they sail.
We shall pray for both you
and your husband's support.
Just as we prayed nightly for the
Sea Snakes' return to good health.
There's no port on the narrow sea we dare
to make an enemy of the Velaryon fleet.
And our enemies?
We have no friends
among the Lannisters.
Tylander served the Hand too
long to turn against him.
An Otto Hightower needs
the Lannister fleet.
Without the Lannisters, we're not like to
find any allies west of the Golden Tooth. no
The Riverlands are
essential, Your Grace.
Pray forgive my bluntness, Your
Grace, but talk of men is moot.
Your cause owns a power...
that has not been seen in this
world since the days of old Valyria.
Dragons!
The Greens have dragons.
They have three
adults, by my count.
We have Cyrax,
Caraxes, and Melis.
Your sons have Vyrmax,
Arrax and Tyraxes.
Bela has Moondancer.
Daemon, none of our
dragons have been to war.
There are also
unclaimed dragons.
Seasmoke still
resides on Drithmar.
Vermithor and Silverwind
dwell on the Dragon Mound.
Still riderless.
Then there are the
three wild dragons,
all of whom nest here.
And who is to ride them?
Dragonstone has
13 to their four.
I also have a score of eggs
incubating in the Dragon Mound.
No.
We need a place to
gather, a toehold,
large enough to
house a sizable host.
Here, at Harrenhal,
we cut off the west,
surround King's Landing
with the dragons,
and we could have every
green head mounted on spikes
before the fucking moon turns.
Your Grace, a ship has
been sighted offshore.
A lone galleon flying a banner
of a three-headed green dragon.
Alert the watchtowers,
sight the skies.
I come at the behest
of the dowager...
Queen Alicent, mother of King
Aegon, second of his name,
lord and protector of
the Seven Kingdoms.
I've been directed to deliver her
message only to Princess Rhaenyra.
Where is the princess?
Princess Reneira.
I'm Queen Rhaenyra now, and you
all are traitors to the realm.
King Aegon Targaryen,
second of his name.
In his wisdom and desire for
peace, he's offering terms.
Acknowledge Aegon as king and swear
obeisance before the Iron Throne.
In exchange, his grace will confirm
your possession of Dragonstone.
It will pass to your true-born
son, Jocerys, upon your death.
Locerys will be confirmed as
the legitimate heir to Driftmark
and all the lands and
holdings of House Velaryon.
Your sons, by Prince Daemon,
will also be given places
of high honour at court.
Aegon the Younger as
the king's squire,
Viserys as his cup-bearer.
Finally, the king,
in his good grace,
will pardon any knight or lord
who conspired against his assent.
I would rather feed
my sons to the dragons
and have them carry
shields and caps
for your drunken
usurper cunt of a king.
Aegon Targaryen sits
the Iron Throne.
He wears the Conqueror's crown,
wields the Conqueror's sword,
has the Conqueror's name.
WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
He was anointed by a
septon of the faith
before the eyes of thousands.
Every symbol of
legitimacy belongs to him.
And then there is Stark, Tully, Baratheon,
houses that have also received and are at
present considering generous
terms from their king.
Stark, Tully, and Baratheon all swore to
me when King Viserys named me his heir.
Stale oaths will not put you
on the Iron Throne, princess.
Succession changed the day
your father sired a son.
I only regret that
you and he were
the last to see the truth of it.
You are no more hand than Eggald
his king, fucking traitor.
Grand Maester.
What the fuck is this?
Queen Alicent has not forgotten the
love you once had for each other.
No blood need be spilled. The
realm can carry on in peace.
Queen Alicent eagerly
awaits your answer.
She can have her answer now, stuffed in her
father's mouth along with his withered cock.
Let's end this mum as far as...
Sir Eric, bring me Lord Hightower
so I may take the pleasure myself.
No.
King's Landing will have my
answer on them on the morning.
It's no easy thing for a
man to be a dragon slayer.
But dragons can kill
dragons and have.
The simple truth is this, we
have more dragons than Aegon.
Viserys spoke often of the Valyrian
histories. I know them well.
When dragons flew to
war, everything burned.
I do not wish to rule over
a kingdom of ash and bone.
Are you considering the High
Tower's terms, Your Grace?
As Queen, what is my true duty
to the realm, Lord Bartimus?
Ensuring peace and unity, or that I
sit the Iron Throne no matter the cost?
What's your father talking?
My father's dead.
And he chose me
as his successor.
To defend the realm, not
cast it headlong into war.
The enemy have declared war.
What are you going
to do about it?
Clear the room.
Does the promise
of war excite you?
It cannot bend the
knee to the Hightowers.
They stole your birthright.
If you could take
the Iron Throne
without putting Otto Hightower's
head on a spike, would you?
Are you not angry?
Well, I should declare
war because I'm angry.
No, because it's your duty
as queen to crush rebellion.
You know my oath reaches
beyond our personal ambitions.
A song of ice and fire.
What?
The coming war against the darkness
in the north will conquer his dream.
But Serah shared it with me
when he named to me Er...
My brother was a slave to
his own man's importance.
Anything to make his feckless
reign appear to have purpose.
Dreams didn't make us kings.
Dragons did.
I never told you.
Did you hear?
I've had men whipped for
falling asleep on their watch.
You are no man.
You abandoned me when
I most needed you,
both our children
stolen from us.
I needed you...
Baylor and Reyna needed you,
and you abandoned us for
more adventure at sea.
Us has always been your way.
I had no other place to turn.
I'd lost everything.
We. Last callers.
We.
I understand we have a new king.
A stranger casts a long
shadow over this family.
Your brother is also dead.
In his haste to bury
you and claim your seat,
he stood before the
king and denounced
Lainore's sons as illegitimate.
Daemon took his head for it.
Heedless ambition has always
been a Valarian weakness.
You were right, Rhaenys.
I reached too far,
and for nothing.
Our pursuit of the Iron
Throne is at an end.
We shall declare for no one.
We will retire to High tide...
to becontent with
our grandchildren.
Jace, Luke and Joff are
claimants to the throne.
Those boys will not be safe
so long as Aegon is king.
Rhaenyra was complicit
in our son's death.
That girl destroys
everything she touches.
That girl is holding the
realm together at present.
Every man standing around the Painted Table
urges her to plunge the realm into war.
Rhaenyra is the only one
who's demonstrated restraint.
The purpose of all this is to build
great grounds, my dear lords, trick is...
to put more of their men in
the ground than your own.
Easy words for a lord who commands
from the safety of his castle.
The Lord of the Tides,
Lord Corlys Velaryon,
And his wife, the Princess
Rhaenys Targaryen.
My lords.
Lord Corlys.
Brings much relief to see
you hale and healthy again.
I'm very sorry about
your father, Princess.
He was a good man.
Where is Damon?
There were other concerns
which demanded the
Prince's attention...
you're declared allies?
Yes too few to win
a war for the throne
well we would also hope to have the
support of houses Aaron Baratheon and stuff
Hope is the fool's ally.
Both Arryn and Baratheon share blood with
my house, but all of them swore oaths to me.
As did House Hightower,
if I remember.
As did you, Lord Corlys.
Your father's realm was
one of justice and honor.
Our houses are bound by
common blood and common cause.
This Hightower
treason cannot stand.
You have the full support
of our fleet and house.
Your grace.
You honor me, Lord Corlys...
Princess Rhaenys,
but, as I said to my Bannermen
I made a promise to my father to
hold the realm strong and united.
If war's first stroke is to
fall, it will not be by my hand.
You do not mean to act.
Taking Caution...
does not mean standing fast...
I wish to know who
my allies are...
before I send them to war
Consequence of my near
demise in the stepstones
Is that we now control them I?
Took care to fully garrison
the territory this time...
a total blockade of the shipping
lanes will be in place in days
if not already the triarchy have
been routed the narrow sea is ours,
if we further seal the gullet...
we can cut off all seaborne travel
and trade to King's Landing.
I should take Maylis and
patrol the gullet myself
When we drain the Narrow Sea,
we can surround King's Landing,
lay siege to the Red Keep, and
force the Green's surrender.
If we're to have enough swords
to surround King's Landing,
we must first secure the support of
Winterfell the Arian Storm's End.
I'll prepare the
ravens, Your Grace.
We should bear those mysteries.
Dragons can fly faster than ravens
and they're more convincing.
Send us.
The prince is right, Your Grace.
Very well.
Prince Jocerys will fly north.
First to the Eyrie to see my
mother's cousin, the Lady Jane Allen.
And then to Winterfell to treat with Lord
Cragan Stark for the support of the North.
Prince Lucerys will fly south to Storm's
End and treat with Lord Boros Baratheon.
We must remind these lords
of the oaths they swore
and the cost of breaking them.
It's been said that as Targaryens,
we are closer to gods than to men.
The Iron Throne puts us
a touch closer, perhaps.
But, if we are to serve
the Seven Kingdoms,
we must answer to their gods.
If you take this errand, you go
as messengers, not as warriors.
You must take no
part in any fighting.
Swear it to me now, under
the eyes of the Seven.
I swear it.
Thank you.
Cregan Stark is close to
your age, then to mine.
I would hope that as men, we
can find some common interest.
Yes, Your Grace.
Storm's End is a short
flight from here.
You have Baratheon blood
from your grandmother, Anise.
And Lord Boros is an
eternally proud man.
You'll be honoured to host
a prince of the realm.
And his dragon.
I expect you will receive
a very warm welcome.
Yes, Mother. To Chris.
Go to it, then.
For stratis, sigela, irudas,
anon, ose, arzuro, utunti,
isim, tos, laosi,
ae, ae, ae, ae.
AHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHH...
I'm Princess Cerys Velaryon.
I bring a message to Lord
Borys from the Queen.
Prince Lucerius Velaryon.
Son of Princess
Runeira Targaryen.
Loporos.
I brought you a
message from my mother.
The Queen.
Yet earlier this day I received
an envoy from the King.
Which is it?
King or Queen?
The House of the Dragon does
not seem to know who rules it.
What's your mother's message?
Where's the bloody maester?
Remind me of my father's oath.
King Agon at least
came with an offer.
My swords and banners
for a marriage pact.
If I do as your mother bids,
which one of my
daughters will you wed?
Boy?
My lord, I'm not free to marry.
I'm already betrothed.
So you come with empty hands.
Go home, pup, and
tell your mother
that the Lord of Storm's
End is not some dog
that she can whistle up at
me to set against her foes.
I shall take your answer
to the Queen, my Lord.
Wait.
My Lord Strong.
Did you really think
that you could just
fly about the realm,
trying to steal my
brother's throne at no cost.
I will not fight you.
I came as a messenger,
not a warrior.
Fight would be little challenge.
No;
I want you to put out your eye.
It's payment for mine.
One will serve.
I would not blind you.
I plan to make a gift
of it to my mother.
No.
Then you are craven
as well as a traitor.
Not here.
Give me your eye, or
I will take it, boss.
Not in my hall.
The boy came as an envoy.
I'll not have blood
shed beneath my roof.
Take Prince Lucerys
back to his dragon.
Now!
Focus!
Pay attention, Arrax!
Be calm!
Listen!
Obey!
Fly, Arrax!
Ahh.
Ha Ha Ha.
Quickly, Turn!
You owe a debt.
Boy!
No, Arrax!
No, Arrax! Serve me!
Np, No, No, No, No, Baker!
No.
Serve me Baker! No.
Baker! No! No!